<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN"
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd">
<book>
  <bookinfo>
    <title>Poor Http / Poor Publisher</title>

    <author>
      <firstname>Ondřej</firstname>

      <surname>Tůma</surname>

      <affiliation>
        <orgname>mcbig@zeropage.cz</orgname>
      </affiliation>
    </author>

    <pubdate></pubdate>
  </bookinfo>

  <chapter>
    <title>Introdution</title>

    <section>
      <title>Introdution</title>

      <para>Poor Http Server is standalone http server, which is designed for
      using python web applications.</para>

      <para>Unlike other projects, this is not framework, but single server
      type application. It is not depended on another special technologies or
      frameworks, only on base python library and it provides base API for
      making python web applications.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>Why choose Poor Http</title>

      <para><itemizedlist>
          <listitem>
            <para>Stand alone server application.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>It's depends only on base Python library, there is no need
            to other special frameworks or libraries.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Base API for writing python web applications allows running
            applications under self users.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Python modules are still stores in memory, so new request
            are serves very quickly. [Single and Threading mode]</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Server could runs in threading and forking mode, so more
            request could be serves in same time.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Easy configuration by ini file, which could be use to
            configuration of web application.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Error and Access Log</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Standard error handlers: 500 Internal Server Error, 400 Not
            Found, 302 Found (redirect), etc.</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>API variability</para>
          </listitem>

          <listitem>
            <para>Base file transport (css, txt, png files)</para>
          </listitem>
        </itemizedlist></para>

      <para>Server is not, and it could be not classic http server. It does
      not support cgi, directory listing or virtual hosting (HTTP/1.1 header).
      It goes well where it's better run python application in server mode. It
      is no need to other http server , but it is recommending to use real
      http server as proxy server before this application. Poor Http server
      application could be use as html gui of some system application for
      example too.</para>
    </section>

    <section>
      <title>BSD Licence</title>

      <para>Copyright (c) 2009, Ondrej Tuma. All rights reserved.</para>

      <para>Redistribution and use in source and binary forms, with or without
      modification, are permitted provided that the following conditions are
      met:</para>

      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Redistributions of source code must retain the above copyright
          notice, this list of conditions and the following disclaimer.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Redistributions in binary form must reproduce the above
          copyright notice, this list of conditions and the following
          disclaimer in the documentation and/or other materials provided with
          the distribution.</para>
        </listitem>

        <listitem>
          <para>Neither the name of the author nor the names of its
          contributors may be used to endorse or promote products derived from
          this software without specific prior written permission.</para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <para>THIS SOFTWARE IS PROVIDED BY THE COPYRIGHT HOLDERS AND
      CONTRIBUTORS "AS IS" AND ANY EXPRESS OR IMPLIED WARRANTIES, INCLUDING,
      BUT NOT LIMITED TO, THE IMPLIED WARRANTIES OF MERCHANTABILITY AND
      FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE ARE DISCLAIMED. IN NO EVENT SHALL
      COPYRIGHT HOLDER BE LIABLE FOR ANY DIRECT, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL,
      SPECIAL, EXEMPLARY, OR CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES (INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED
      TO, PROCUREMENT OF SUBSTITUTE GOODS OR SERVICES; LOSS OF USE, DATA, OR
      PROFITS; OR BUSINESS INTERRUPTION) HOWEVER CAUSED AND ON ANY THEORY OF
      LIABILITY, WHETHER IN CONTRACT, STRICT LIABILITY, OR TORT (INCLUDING
      NEGLIGENCE OR OTHERWISE) ARISING IN ANY WAY OUT OF THE USE OF THIS
      SOFTWARE, EVEN IF ADVISED OF THE POSSIBILITY OF SUCH DAMAGE.</para>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter>
    <title>Installation</title>

    <section>
      <title>Installation</title>

      <programlisting>$ tar xjf poorhttp-20091124.tar.bz2
$ mkdir -p /srv/run /srv/log /srv/app /srv/www
$ mv poorhttp /srv/
$ mv etc /srv/
$ mv init.d/poorhttp /etc/init.d/
$ /etc/init.d/poorhttp start</programlisting>
    </section>
  </chapter>
</book>
